tasb.org 2019-04-01

# TASB Website Privacy Policy

## General

This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) covers how the Texas Association of School Boards, Inc. (“TASB”) handles personal information collected and received from or through the TASB website, the online applications that TASB makes available to you, and our use of information collected about you through our social media pages (the TASB website, online applications, and social media pages are collectively referred to herein as the “Site”). As used in this Policy, the term “TASB” shall also include its wholly-owned subsidiary, First Public, LLC, and all affiliated entities to which TASB or its subsidiary provides website services on this Site (e.g., TASB Legal Assistance Fund, TASB Risk Management Fund, The Local Government Purchasing Cooperative, TASB Energy Cooperative, Lone Star Investment Pool, and TASB Benefits Cooperative).

Personal information is information about you that ordinarily would not be publicly available and that identifies you individually, such as your name, residential address, personal e-mail address, geolocation (your mobile internet device’s longitudinal and latitudinal information), and personal phone number. This Policy does not apply to the practices of entities or people that TASB does not employ, manage, or control.

## Accessing the Site and Personal Information Collection

You are not required to be a TASB member or to provide personal information to access certain parts of the Site. When you access the Site without actively providing any personal information, we may collect limited technical information, such as your IP address and geolocation. We also use cookies and analytics as described below. 

Certain parts of the Site do require that you provide us with personal information for access to or use of those parts. For example, if you register to use a portion of the Site that is password-protected, you may be required to provide information as described in the “Registration and Forms” section below. 

## Cookies

TASB uses cookies (text files placed on your hard drive by a web server) to help personalize and maximize your experience and time online. Cookies are not used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. They are uniquely assigned to your computer and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. We use cookies to improve the Site and to facilitate your use of the Site. (Read more about how to manage cookies in Terms and Conditions of Use.)

## Registration and Forms

From the Site, you may register to attend events, obtain information and services, participate in outreach and advocacy initiatives, answer survey questions and other inquiries, and subscribe to receive communications from TASB. These registrations may require you to provide the following:

  * Contact information such as your name, address, phone number, and e-mail address
  * Demographic information such as ZIP Code and date of birth
  * Payment information to invoice for products or services purchased

We may use this information, and any other information you provide, to effect transactions or provide services for which the information was provided, to contact you with additional information and updates, and to analyze use of our Site and services.

In some cases, this information may be collected and stored by third parties and therefore may also be subject to their privacy policies. You may review any such policies by contacting those third parties or by reviewing the policies posted on their websites.

## Online Forums and Message Boards

The Site makes forums and message boards available to our members. Information you disclose in these areas may become public, so exercise caution when deciding what information to disclose.

## Links

The Site contains links to other websites. TASB is not responsible for the privacy practices of sites other than our own. We encourage you to be aware of the privacy statements on other websites and to read these statements.

## Protection of Information

Some areas of the Site are secured and can only be accessed using unique login credentials. You must have a specific user identifier (user ID) and password to access resources through any password-protected portions of the Site. Your login credentials and password are for your use only and strictly confidential. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of those credentials, and are responsible for all activity occurring on the Site using your login credentials and password. You are strictly prohibited from any sharing of your login credentials and/or password with any other person(s) and from any use of your login credentials other than for your use of the Site in compliance with these Terms. 

## Online Purchases

TASB uses a third-party service provider site to effect purchases of materials offered on the Site. That service provider uses industry-standard practices and software to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal, identifying information. Firewalls and Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption protect credit card information you make available for any online purchases. Please note, however, that no form of electronic communication is 100 percent secure, and you should use caution whenever providing personal information online.

## Social Media

The collection and use of information on social media websites and applications are governed by their own privacy policies. Please remember that any information posted on or through the TASB pages such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Pinterest, or on other social media pages or channels, is subject to the policies and practices of the applicable social media channel.

We may receive personal information from a social media site platform or application when you connect through a social media feed, post content, or otherwise interact with us using social media tools. For example, we may receive basic Facebook account information (name, e‑mail, gender, birthday, current city, and profile picture URL) through Facebook. Also, when you “like” us, or send a “Tweet” to us through a social media channel, we may receive your username, handle, and any other available personal information from the social media site or application. All information received from social media sites and applications is treated and used in the same manner and for the same purposes as described in this Policy with respect to similar information we obtain through the Site. 

## Third-Party Data Collection/Online Tracking

We use service providers such as Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Google AdWords, and Kentico to help us understand and improve the usage of the Site and the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. Google Analytics may use cookies, your IP address or an anonymous identifier as well as certain information from your browser, together with other information about you and your visits to our Site and other websites, so that we, Google, or third parties may provide you with advertisements about goods and services of interest to you on our Site and other websites (including through Google search results pages) and/or to provide analytical information about our Site. If you would like more information about advertising networks, including choices about the use of information by Google and other companies for multi-site advertising purposes, go to [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and [optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/). Also, Google offers a Google Analytics browser add-on (designed to be compatible only with certain browsers) to provide website visitors the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics. That add-on may be obtained [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en); other Google privacy controls are available [here](https://privacy.google.com/take-control.html); and you can manage your Google ad settings [here](https://adssettings.google.com/).

Currently, various Internet browsers offer a “do not track” or “DNT” option that uses a DNT header to indicate the DNT preference setting on the browser. TASB does not track your activity over time and across different websites or online services, and thus we do not currently respond to browsers’ DNT signals with respect to the Site. We do not permit our third-party service providers to collect information from the Site for other websites or for their own purposes other than as described in this Policy.

## Geolocation Information

We may receive information about your geolocation and your mobile internet device when you use our Site.  We may use this information to provide you with location-based services and information.  Most mobile internet devices allow you to turn off geolocation, and we encourage you to contact your device manufacturer for detailed instructions on how to do so.

## Children’s Privacy

We are committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations regarding the collection, storage, and use of personal information of minors under the age of 18, including the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998.

We do not collect personal information from minors under the age of 18. Individuals under the age of 18 are not permitted to use the Site without the supervision of a parent or legal guardian. We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under the age of 18 or knowingly allow such persons to register for an online account or to place orders or provide personal information through the Site. If we learn that someone under the age of 18 has provided any personal information through the Site, we will remove and permanently delete that information as soon as reasonably possible.

If you are a parent or guardian who believes that your minor under the age of 18 has submitted personal information or other information to us without your consent, please contact us using the contact information provided below. Once we verify that you are the parent or legal guardian, we will cooperate with you to discuss what, if any, personal information we have collected about your child and how that information may have been shared or used.

## Updates to This Policy

TASB may modify this Policy at any time. When changes are made, we will update the version date at the bottom of the Policy. Your use of TASB’s Services following these changes means that you accept the revised Policy.

## Correcting Your Information

We strive to assure the correctness of the information we maintain. If the information we have about you is inaccurate, we will correct the information in a manner as timely as possible. To provide us with corrections, please contact us in any of the following ways:

  * Send an e-mail message with corrections to [webmaster@tasb.org](mailto:webmaster@tasb.org).
  * Send mail with corrections to P.O. Box 400, Austin, Texas 78767.
  * Call us at 512.467.0222.

## Security

We employ reasonable security methods to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure correct use of your information. However, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be perfectly secure. As a result, while we try to protect your information, we cannot ensure or guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.
